Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
- Series VIII: Poetry, undated, 1958-1988
  - The Cantilever Rainbow
    - "Ode"
      - Typescript and copy, 1959 March 30 - April 23 (Box 30:, Folder 951)
      - Typescript and copies, 1961 September (Box 30:, Folder 952)
      - Typescript and copies, 1961 December 31 (Box 30:, Folder 953)
      - Typescript copy, 1962 January (Box 30:, Folder 954)
    - "Play 1" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 955)
    - "Play 2" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 956)
    - "A Play: In a Bull's Eye" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 31:, Folder 957)
    - "Poem-Play: A Beautiful Day"
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 31:, Folder 958)
      - Directorial Notes, after 1965 December (Box 31:, Folder 959)
    - ["snow melting"] [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 960)
    - "Song" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 961)
    - "Spring Song" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 962)
    - "A Springtime Musical: the 50,000 Dogwood Trees... " [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 963)
    - ["The Sun"]
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 31:, Folder 964)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 31:, Folder 965)
    - "Sun If Only" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 966)
    - "Yuri Gagarin and William Shakespeare" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 967)
    - Preliminary typescript, undated (Box 31:, Folder 968)
    - "Duplicates, finals, semis, and discards" [tss], undated (Box 31:, Folder 969)
    - Typescript, [1964] November 22 - December 7 (Box 31:, Folder 970)
    - Partial typescript with instructions to printer, ca. 1965 (Box 31:, Folder 971)
    - Typescript with instructions to printer, ca. 1965 (Box 31:, Folder 972)
    - "Duet" [sketches], undated (Box 31:, Folder 973)
    - Acknowledgements page [mss], ca. 1965 (Box 31:, Folder 974)
    - "Name-Calling at the Sun" title page [sketch], undated (Box 31:, Folder 975)
    - "Ode" [sketches], undated (Box 31:, Folder 976)
    - "Duet" [layout sketch], undated (Box 31:, Folder 977)
    - "Duet" [layout sketches], 1964 March 9 (Box 31:, Folder 978)
    - "Ode" [layout sketches], undated (Box 31:, Folder 979)
    - "Duet," large partial dummy, undated (Box 31:, Folder 980)
    - "Name-Calling at the Sun," first dummy and copy, undated (Box 31:, Folder 981)
    - "Name-Calling at the Sun," smal dummies, undated (Box 31:, Folder 982)
    - "Ode," partial dummies, ca. 1962 October 27 (Box 31:, Folder 983)
    - "Ode," partial pasted dummies, copies, and extras, undated (Box 31:, Folder 984)
    - "Ode," large dummy, undated (Box 31:, Folder 985)
    - "Ode," printed dummies, undated (Box 31:, Folder 986)
    - "Ode," second dummy, 1961 October 17 (Box 31:, Folder 987)
    - "Song" ("I'd Much Rather Sit There in the Sun"), materials for stand-alone book, undated (Box 31:, Folder 988)
    - Partial illustrated dummy, undated (Box 31:, Folder 989)
    - "First dummy," [paste-up dummy], undated (Box 31:, Folder 990)
    - Paste-up dummy and copy, undated (Box 32:, Folder 991)
    - Cuts from galley prints, ca. 1965 (Box 32:, Folder 992)
    - Partial galleys annotated by Michael di Capua, Pantheon Books, 1965 January (Box 32:, Folder 993)
    - Galleys and notes, ca. 1965 February 20 (Box 32:, Folder 994)
    - Proofs, ca. 1965 (Box 32:, Folder 995)
    - Dust jackets, ca. 1965 (Box 32:, Folder 996)
    - Flyers, undated (Box 55:, Folder 1689)
    - Clippings, ca. 1966 (Box 32:, Folder 997)
    - Programs, undated (Box 32:, Folder 998)
    - Reviews, 1966 (Box 32:, Folder 999)
    - Unidentified materials, undated (Box 32:, Folder 1000)
  - Category Poems (unpublished) [contents list], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1001)
  - "The Cherries and the Berries and the Wild Blue Sea" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1002)
  - "Child in Harriet Abel's Class" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1003)
  - "Chinese History" [copy], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1004)
  - "Christopher Columbus Crazy" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1005)
  - The Cliffs of Nowhere (unpublished) [tss, mss, dummies], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1006)
  - "A Cold Place I Know" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1007)
  - "Cold Wet Day" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1008)
  - Collaborations with Freya Littledale, undated (Box 32:, Folder 1009)
  - Collaborations with "Jean,", undated (Box 32:, Folder 1010)
  - , undated (Box 32:)
  - Collection submitted anonymously, undated (Box 32:, Folder 1011)
  - "Commas" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1012)
  - "Compplaint" (unpublished poem) [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1013)
  - "Complaint to the Moon" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1014)
  - "Connected to Leonard Cohen's SUZANNE" [tss and copy], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1015)
  - "Copy Cat" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1016)
  - "Cosmopera" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1017)
  - "Country Song / City Song" [tss and copies], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1018)
  - "Crosstown Street Song" [tss; See also "Dance Song."], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1019)
  - "dance" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1020)
  - "Dance Dream" [tss and mss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1021)
  - "Dance Song" [tss; See also "Crosstown Street Song."], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1022)
  - "Dark and the Rain" [tss and copies], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1023)
  - "Death of Onward" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1024)
  - "December Blues for John" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1025)
  - "The Deluded Streetlamp" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1026)
  - "Depression Poem" [tss and copies; See also ["wits / stars"] in Under Twenty.], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1027)
  - "Dewnog" [copies], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1028)
  - "Diane with her Black Top" [tss and copy], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1029)
  - "Diary" [mss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1030)
  - "A Do-It-Yourself Show" [copy], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1031)
  - "dog-wif-wings" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1032)
  - Down Here, clippings, undated (Box 32:, Folder 1033)
  - "A Dozen Ifs" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1034)
  - "Dream and Associations" [tss, mss, copy], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1035)
  - "A Dream for Breton" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1036)
  - "Dream for Breton III" [tss and mss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1037)
  - "A Dream--You Can Reflect the Universe" [tss and copies], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1038)
  - "The Drunken Plane" [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1039)
  - "Duet" ["If I... "] [tss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1040)
    See also "Song and Act."
  - "Duet #2" [mss], undated (Box 32:, Folder 1041)
  - "Earth Song" [mss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1042)
  - "Echoes / Kind and Hated Unknown Sea" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1043)
  - "Electropera" [mss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1044)
  - "Epic Poem about Child Hero" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1045)
  - "Etienne Takes You" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1046)
  - "Everyday How Your Who" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1047)
  - "Evolution of 2 Verses" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1048)
  - "Expurgated Prevert" [tss and mss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1049)
  - "Fallen Angel" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1050)
  - "Fine Day" [tss and mss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1051)
  - "First Came John" [copy], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1052)
  - Five Poems (unpublished) [copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1053)
  - "For a Peanut Baby Still in its Shell" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1054)
  - ["For Glenn"] [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1055)
  - "For John" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1056)
  - "For Paul Celan" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1057)
  - ["For the Birthday"] [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1058)
  - "Found Poem" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1059)
  - "Fountains" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1060)
  - "Four Prose Poems" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1061)
  - "Freedom Voice" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1062)
  - "From Now on I'm Going to Have Stars in My Head" [tss and mss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1063)
  - "From Now on I'm Going to Have Stars in My Head" [tss and mss], 1959 June (Box 33:, Folder 1064)
  - "From Seasalt" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1065)
  - "From the French of Onward Folie" [copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1066)
  - "Front Page" [tss], 1960 September (Box 33:, Folder 1067)
  - "Fruitcake over Moshulu Parkway" [copy], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1068)
  - "Garden" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1069)
  - "A Giant Because Flips its Lid" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1070)
  - "Girl Hero" [tss and mss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1071)
  - "Girl's Song" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1072)
  - "Give Her Back to the Indians" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1073)
  - "Give Me" [tss, mss, and copy], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1074)
  - "Gone Song" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1075)
  - "Good Bad Poem" [mss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1076)
  - Grand Motel (unpublished) [tss and mss], 1971 June (Box 33:, Folder 1077)
  - "Grandma and the Prince" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1078)
  - "Gravity" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1079)
  - "Green House, Pink Mountain" [tss, mss, copies, layouts], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1080)
  - "Half Nemesis" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1081)
  - "Happy Ever After" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1082)
  - "Happy Like" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1083)
  - "Hardluck" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1084)
  - "Hark Hark" [tss and copies], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1085)
  - "Hark, my Love, Hark" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1086)
  - "Hart Crane Script" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1087)
  - "He" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1088)
  - "A High Wind in the Syntax" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1089)
  - A Horse Opera with Wings (unpublished collection) [tss and paste-ups], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1090)
  - "Hot in the Head" [copy], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1091)
  - "How" [tss], undated (Box 33:, Folder 1092)
  - How to Write Twenty Poems (unpublished)
    - Contents list, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1093)
    - Drafts, set 1, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1094)
    - Drafts, set 2, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1095)
    - Drafts, set 3, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1096)
    - Drafts, set 4, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1097)
    - Drafts, set 5, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1098)
    - Drafts, set 6, ca. 1965-1970 (Box 34:, Folder 1099)
    - Advanced Dates, undated (Box 34:, Folder 1100)
    - Revised drafts, 1969-1973 (Box 34:, Folder 1101)
    - "Backward Go" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1102)
    - "Little Abandoned One" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1103)
    - "Pomegranite" [tss and copy], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1104)
    - Untitled sections [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1105)
    - "Write Anything and Don't" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1106)
  - "Hunting Song" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1107)
  - "Hymn" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1108)
  - "I Am" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1109)
  - "I Bring" [copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1110)
  - "I Could Never Get Along with History" [mss and tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1111)
  - "I Hate" / "Grand Hotel" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1112)
  - "I Hate You" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1113)
  - "I Look" / "I Look for It" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1114)
  - "I Love You with the Aid of Artaud" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1115)
  - "I Love You with the Aid of Joe Ceravolo" [tss, mss, and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1116)
  - "I Love You with the Aid of Julian Beck" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1117)
  - "I Love You with the Aid of St. Mark's on the Bowery" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1118)
  - "I Love You with the Help of Genet" [tss and copies], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1119)
  - "I Never Could Get Along with... " [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1120)
  - "I Say It" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1121)
  - "I Wonder Where is John" [tss], undated (Box 34:, Folder 1122)
  - "If I Were Freedom" [program], undated (Box 35:, Folder 1123)
  - If Only
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1124)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 35, Folder 1125)
    - "Last Batch" [tss], undated (Box 35:, Folder 1126)
    - Annotated typescript and letter, ca. 1959 March 1 (Box 35:, Folder 1127)
    - Typescript and copy, 1959 March 23 (Box 35:, Folder 1128)
    - Typescript, 1959 March 26 (Box 35:, Folder 1129)
    - Annotated typescript, [1959] June 20 (Box 35:, Folder 1130:)
    - Typescript, [1959] June 30 (Box 35:, Folder 1131)
    - Annotated typescript, 1959 July 8 (Box 35:, Folder 1132)
    - Annotated typescript, [1959] July 29 (Box 35:, Folder 1133)
    - "Last" annotated typescript, 1959 October 23 (Box 35:, Folder 1134)
    - "If Only" short version, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1135)
    - Blurb and bibliography, ca. 1959 (Box 35:, Folder 1136)
    - Illustrated dummy pages, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1137)
    - Paste-up dummy, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1138)
    - Mock-up, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1139)
    - Toad Press book covers, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1140)
    - Early poems, typescripts and copies, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1141)
    - Unbound copies, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1142)
    - Tributes by other authors, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1143)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1144)
  - "The Illiterate Heart" [tss], undated (Box 35:, Folder 1145)
  - "In a Bull's Eye II" [tss], undated (Box 35:, Folder 1146)
  - "In Celebration of Tricycle and Scissorgrinder Week" [tss and copies; See also "Somehow Connected with Lorca."], undated (Box 35:, Folder 1147)
  - "In Progress" (long poem) [See also When I Walk I Change the Earth.]
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1148)
    - Drafts and copies, undated (Box 35:, Folder 1149)
  - "In the Beginnings," Version A [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1150)
  - "In the Beginnings," Version B [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1151)
  - "In the Early Yeats of My Heart" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1152)
  - "In the Spring" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1153)
  - In the Suburbs of Physics" [tss and copy], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1154)
  - "Into the Air" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1155)
  - "Intoxication" [tss and copy], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1156)
  - "Isy" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1157)
  - "It" [mss and tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1158)
  - "It Figures" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1159)
  - "It's Just so Delightful Here" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1160)
  - "Knock" [tss and production notes], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1161)
  - "Landlord Song" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1162)
  - "Leda and" [tss, mss, and copies], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1163)
  - "A Leftover Dream" [tss], 1959 October 19 (Box 36:, Folder 1164)
  - Letters from Mike [copy], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1165)
  - "Light Poem" [tss and copies], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1166)
  - "Like Clouds" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1167)
  - "Little Battery, the World-Machine is Waiting for Your Charge" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1168)
  - "Little Lion" [tss and copy], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1169)
  - "Little Nut Song" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1170)
  - "Little Shell" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1171)
  - "Lone Fragment" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1172)
  - Looking at a Painting
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 36:, Folder 1173)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 36:, Folder 1174)
    - Partial dummy, undated (Box 36:, Folder 1175)
  - "Lord Randall" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1176)
  - "Loud Blue Song" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1177)
  - "Love" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1178)
  - "Love and the Invention of Punctuation" [mss, sketches, and copies], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1179)
  - "Love Fragment" [tss and copies], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1180)
  - "Love Poem" [copy], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1181)
  - "Love Poems for the Sun" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1182)
  - "Love Stuff" [tss; See also Big and Little in Series II.], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1183)
  - Love to Lorca" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1184)
  - "Lullabye" (unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1185)
  - "Lullabye 2" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1186)
  - The MacDowell Colony [brochure], 1977 (Box 36:, Folder 1187)
  - "The Magic Bathtub" [tss and copy], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1188)
  - "Making Sandwich Kisses" (poem play) [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1189)
  - "Manifesto" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1190)
  - "Many Waters" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1191)
  - "Matador Circus Acetalyne Burgundy" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1192)
  - "Mathmatichorale" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1193)
  - "The Messiah Tree" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1194)
  - Messy Vitality (unpublished collection) [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1195)
  - Metaphor Collection [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1196)
  - "Methinks" [tss], undated (Box 36:, Folder 1197)
  - Minestrone
    - Preliminary contents, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1198)
    - Compilation, set 1, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1199)
    - Compilation, set 2, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1200)
    - Compilation, set 3, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1210)
    - Compilation, set 4, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1202)
    - Compilation, set 5, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1203)
    - Compilation, set 6, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1204)
    - Compilation, set 7, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1205)
    - Short pieces considered [tss and mss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1206)
    - "Birthday," [tss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1207)
    - "Himself," [tss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1208)
    - "Little Cloud" [tss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1209)
    - "A Long Camel,", undated (Box 37:, Folder 1210)
    - "Lullabye" [mss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1211)
    - "Lullabye" [tss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1212)
    - "Song" [tss], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1213)
    - "Strange Boy" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1214)
    - "Troubadour Song" [tss and copies], undated (Box 37:, Folder 1215)
    - Early illustrated manuscript, 1975 September 2 (Box 37:, Folder 1216)
    - Early typescript, 1976 September (Box 38:, Folder 1217)
    - "Version I" [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1218)
    - "Version I," Editor's suggested cuts [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1219)
    - "Semi-final" [tss], ca. 1980 August 1 (Box 38:, Folder 1220)
    - Suggested editor cuts from "Semi-final" typescript, ca. 1980 August (Box 38:, Folder 1221)
    - Typescript, 1981 February 5 (Box 38:, Folder 1222)
    - Illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 38:, Folder 1223)
    - Layout sketch, undated (Box 38:, Folder 1224)
    - Partial printed dummy, undated (Box 38:, Folder 1225)
    - Partial copy of first proof, 1975 September 2 (Box 38:, Folder 1226)
    - Annotated page proofs, ca. 1981 (Box 38:, Folder 1227)
    - Page proofs with annotations by Krauss, ca. 1981 (Box 38:, Folder 1228)
    - Copyright registration, 1981 July (Box 38:, Folder 1229)
    - List of previous publications, undated (Box 37:, Folder 1230)
    - List for permissions, undated (Box 38:, Folder 1231)
    - Reviews, undated (Box 38:, Folder 1232)
  - "Misunderstanding" [copy], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1233)
  - "Moby Bloom" [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1234)
  - "Montauk Poem" [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1235)
  - Month poems [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1236)
  - "The Moon Sandwiches" [tss], 1959 October 19 (Box 38:, Folder 1237)
  - "Morning Song and Dance" [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1238)
  - "Most Repulsive Poem of the Year" [tss and copies], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1239)
  - "Mother-and-Child Duet" [tss], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1240)
  - "Movie" [tss and copies], undated (Box 38:, Folder 1241)
  - "My Beautiful IT" [tss and copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1242)
  - "My Drunken Boat My Red Shoes" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1243)
  - "My Favorite" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1244)
  - "My Friends on a Friday Morning" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1245)
  - "My Japanese Heart" [tss and copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1246)
  - "My Little Italian Cousin Loves" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1247)
  - "My Own Native Reverdy" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1248)
  - "My Worst Dream for Andre Breton" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1249)
  - "Narcissus" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1250)
  - "Nemesis Sonnet" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1251)
  - New Collection (unpublished) [tss and copies; Cover envelope in oversize.], ca. 1969? (Box 39:, Folder 1252)
  - New Collection (unpublished) cover envelope, ca. 1969? (Box 55:, Folder 1688)
  - Newsletters
    - Flyers, undated (Box 39:, Folder 1253)
    - Programs, undated (Box 39:, Folder 1254)
    - Reviews, 10 March 1966 (Box 39:, Folder 1255)
  - "Night of the Kabuki" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1256)
  - "Night Song" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1257)
  - "The Nightengale Factory" [tss and copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1258)
  - "Nineteen Ways of Looking at Madison Avenue" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1259)
  - "Note" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1260)
  - "Notes for Dog Star" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1261)
  - "Notsonnet" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1262)
  - "Not-sonnets of Onward Bloom" [tss and mss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1263)
  - "Noun with the Swelling Belly" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1264)
  - "Now That I Am in Fairfield Country and Can Think" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1265)
  - "Nut Song" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1266)
  - "Nut Talking to the Moon" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1267)
  - "Nutritionewsicale" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1268)
    See also "Duet" ["If I.. ."] and "Song and Act."
  - "N.Y." [mss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1269)
  - "O" [tss and copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1270)
  - "O Book" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1271)
  - "Ocean-Word-Play" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1272)
  - "Oh!" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1273)
  - "Oh! Bit" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1274)
  - "Oh Oh Oh Oh Oh Oh" [copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1275)
  - "Old Hotstuff" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1276)
  - "On Receiving News of a Fellowship At" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1277)
  - "On the Edge" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1278)
  - "Once Again" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1279)
  - "One Dream" [tss and copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1280)
  - "One-liners" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1281)
  - "One Who" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1282)
  - "Onward" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1283)
  - "Onward Carlos Onward" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1284)
  - "ou Donc se Termine la Femme" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1285)
  - "Out of the Corners"/"Under the Influence Of" [tss and copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1286)
  - "The Parade" [tss and copies], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1287)
  - Physics and All That" [tss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1288)
  - "Picture Book" [mss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1289)
  - "Pictures" [mss], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1290)
  - "Play with Songs Music Lights Balloons" [tss and copy; See also The Little King, the Little Queen, the Little Monster in Series II.], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1291)
  - "Playing with Titles" [copy], undated (Box 39:, Folder 1292)
  - The Pocket Follies [programs], 1963 (Box 55:, Folder 1684)
  - The Pocket Follies [clippings], 1963 (Box 40:, Folder 1293)
  - "Poem" ["For God's sake, my friend... ] [tss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1294)
  - "Poem-Act" [copy], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1295)
  - "Poem Act Dance" [tss and copies], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1296)
  - "Poem-Baby" [tss and mss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1297)
  - "Poem-Diary" [tss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1298)
  - "Poem-Episode" [tss and copy], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1299)
  - "Poem for Publishers" [tss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1300)
  - "Poem of the Curtains" [tss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1301)